A Guide to the John W. Sewell papers, Accession 2009:075 FA1274
Rockefeller Archive Center
John W. Sewell papers, Accession 2009:075
1970s-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Sewell, John W.
Overseas Development Council
FA1274
3.93 Cubic Feet 3 standard record storage boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
As received.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred and donated to the RAC by John W. Sewell in 2009.
Biographical / Historical
John W. Sewell served as President of the Overseas Development Council.
Scope and Contents
The papers primarily document Sewell's activities with the Overseas Development Council and consist of reports, proposals, correspondence, memoranda, conference proceedings and publications in the areas of US-Foreign Aid reform, the World Bank, IMF, and other areas of economic development interest.
- Michigan State University and ODC - Development Cooperation Project, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- House Task Force on Foreign Aid Reform, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- US Aid Reform, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- USAID Tidewater Conference - Celebrating Thirty Years of Development, Cooperation, and Progress, Washington, D.C., 1998 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Civil Society - Pocantico, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- DACOR Bacon House Foundation Conference, Washington D.C. - The Future of Foreign Aid (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Baker Institute, 2000 April 9-10 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Nigeria Roundtable, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Nigeria Trip, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Foreign Aid files, 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11-16)
- Concessional Banking, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Multilateral Development Bank Concessional, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Overseas Development Council Conference - The Future of the World Bank, 1986 June 23-24 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- The Multilateral Conference on the Future of MDB Concessional Lending (Schloss Munchenwiler - Munchenwiler, Switzerland), 1997 March 3-4 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Pre-Cancun Journalist Seminar, 1981 October 7; 9; 13; 15 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Global Economic Summit - Phase II (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
- World Summit for Social Development Project (WSSD), 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 25-27)
- United States Budget for a New World Order Project - Promoting National Security and Advancing America's Interests Abroad, FY 1992 - John W. Sewell and Peter M. Storm, Overseas Development Council (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Alternative Budget 1993, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 29-33)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - Background Materials on Foreign Assistance - Report of the Task Force on Foreign Assistance to the Committee on Foreign Affairs U.S House of Representatives, 1989 February (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - The Foreign Policy Project - What Future for Aid (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - Foreign Affairs - Foreign Aid and Gramm - Rudman, John W. Sewell and Christine E. Contee, 1987 Summer (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - A Global Economic Summit, 1999 February 16 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - Strengthening Civil Society's Contribution to Development: The Role of Official Development Assistance - Report on a Conference Organized by the Overseas Development Council and the Synergos Institute. (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - ODC in the 21st Century - ANNUAL REPORT - 1998 Annual Report (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - A Proposal for a Cooperative Agreement Between the Overseas Development Council and the U.S. Agency for International Development, 1999 December (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - Overseas Development Council Publications, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - About the Overseas Development Council (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - Overseas Development Council, Annual Report, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - Overseas Development Council, Annual Report, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - Overseas Development Council Publications (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - About the Overseas Development Council (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Reports, Proposals and Memoranda - ODC in the 21st Century - ANNUAL REPORT, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- ODC Annual Reports and Publications, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Global Engagement Budget, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- New Global-Development Agenda, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Program Development, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- ODC Annual Reports and pamphlets, 1970s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Foreign Aid Report (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Aid - Sinding Project, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Bipartisan Dialogue, 2000 May (Box 3, Folder 42)
- ODC View Point, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- ODC Books in Brief (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Alternative Budget, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 45)
- ODC papers, 1983-2000 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Cancun Global Summit, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- WTO Article - Sewell-Sutherland, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- IMF Working Group, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 49-50)
- IMF Report, 2000 April-May (Box 3, Folder 51)